In my moment of triumph,
all was taken away from me.
Though I was stronger
than ever before,
I was betrayed by those
who should have worshipped me--
my own people,<
the citizens of Imperium,
their minds twisted
by the lies of the Ninja.
[screaming]
I thought I was dead.
I'm sure
you all thought the same,
but I survived.
I found myself alone,
in a forsaken place--
the Land of Monsters.
For months,
I battled the hideous creatures
that roam that savage land,
with one goal fueling me--
Revenge.
The Citizens of Imperium,
the Ninja,
they all had to pay
for taking
what was rightfully mine.
I escaped
from that wretched land,
but I was gravely injured.
The betrayal of my people
and the Ninja
nearly led to my destruction,
yet my fury would not die,
and fate
had more in store for me.
[Dr. LaRow] You're awake.
My experimental
medical treatments
must be working.
LaRow?
All hail the Good Empress.
[Empress Beatrix] I have been
to the abyss and back,
and have the scars to prove it, but you,
and only you, my Loyalists,
never wavered in your faith
in my almighty power.
You will stand by my side
when I retake the kingdom
that is rightfully mine!
As most of you know,
this is the fabled
Weapon of Desolation,
the item responsible
for the deluge
of out-of-control
Elemental Monsters
plaguing the Merged Lands.
Control of this weapon
means control
of these deadly beings.
It gives one
the ability to create
and lead
an army of untold power.
Our hidden Loyalists
have obtained both halves
of the armament,
and will be delivering them
to us today.
Then we will finally
fully assemble
the Weapon of Desolation.
With my army
of Elemental Monsters,
all who betrayed me,
all who questioned
my divine right,
will fall before me,
and I will show them no mercy!
[Loyalists]
All hail the Good Empress!
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪♪
[gasping]
What the...?
Ah! Ow.
[wincing] Oh, right.
Dr. LaRow blasted me.
That was an annoying voice
I never wanted to hear again.
Blech.
Did they find the oldest prison
in Ninjago to put me in?
Okay, whoever was here last
must've gotten bored
and made a friend.
Trust me, Mr. Smiley,
I've been in worse situations.
I should be out of here
in no time.
H'yah!
[groaning]
Ow!
At least no one saw that.
Except for you.
Please don't tell anyone.
[voices echoing through ducts]
...worn out relic.
[LaRow] While I, of course,
don't believe
it's "supernatural",
the proof of the Weapon's power
has been made obvious
all over the Merged Lands,
even if I have not yet uncovered
its scientific foundation,
and I determined
these are the "incantations",
as they say,
that separated the weapon
into two pieces,
apparently written
by the First Spinjitzu Master
himself.
[Empress Beatrix]
I don't care who wrote them!
Will they work?
Based on my research,
if these incantations
are reversed,
like reversing a calculation,
the result
should combine the halves,
empowering the Weapon
and its wielder
beyond all comprehension.
[Empress Beatrix]
And you're certain this tablet
is not some kind of trick?
An outlander fraud?
I traveled to a previously
unknown realm for this.
It's likely I'm the only human
who's been there
since the Weapon of Desolation
was disposed of millennia ago.
[Lead Loyalist] Dr. LaRow,
we extracted this
from the Tree of Madness,
as expected.
You were able to retrieve this
without being detected?
[Lead Loyalist] We had...
a run-in with some Ninja,
but we trapped them in a cave.
Won't be seeing them
for a while,
if ever again.
You had better hope
that's true.
You're dismissed.
As promised,
one half of the Weapon.
I am told the second sliver
is on its way from Umbrasylvis
as we speak.
[metal claw clacking]
I will prove
you have no reason to doubt me.
All hail the Good Empress.
[wobbling]
Whoa! [grunting]
[coughing]
"Weapon of Desolation"?
That can't be good.
[exhaling weakly]
How long does a typical
Trial of the Green Ninja take?
[speaking telepathically]
No two trials are the same,
and I would not hold out
such hope
for your friend Lloyd.
[Arin]
I'm never going to lose hope.
Lloyd faces danger
all the time.
[telepathically]
That is the problem.
It is nearly impossible
to stay idealistic
when you know so much
about this world.
[roaring]
[snarling]
[Lloyd] I'm here to face
my greatest enemy...
Who is that?
Ras? Garmadon?
The Overlord?
Maybe an angry Source Dragon,
or someone else
that secretly hates me,
and I don't know?
Arin's not still mad at me,
is he?
[sighing]
Worrying won't do me any good.
I just need to focus.
This is the only way
to achieve my True Potential
as the Green Ninja.
Home?
How?
This can't be real.
Just a vision.
But... why?
Hello, Lloyd.
My greatest enemy is...
me?
H'ah!
H'yah!
Okay, Plan C...
I got nothing.
Don't judge me,
I don't see you coming up
with any ideas.
If that Empress Beatrix
and Dr. LaRow
have some powerful weapon,
it's up to me to stop them,
but I'm stuck
in this dusty old jail.
Ah!
Seriously?
It's just dirt?
[laughing]
Dr. LaRow
really should've sprung
for the full renovation.
In case you missed it,
Mr. Smiley,
I am an Elemental Master
of Earth.
You know,
like this entire floor
is made out of.
Yeah, I know my powers
have been wonky,
you don't have to give me
that look.
Stand back.
Huah!
[powers fritzing]
[groaning in frustration]
Yeah, yeah, keep laughing.
Whoa!
[screaming]
[grunting impact far below]
[alert blaring]
[♪♪♪]
You, uh... I-I mean me...
I'm not my own worst enemy.
You would want to take
the easy way out.
Why don't you blame
someone else for your problems,
like you usually do?
Your dad.
Ras.
The Merge.
Never realizing
the real problem all along.
Me?
I'm the real problem?
You're not a real leader,
that's for sure.
What?
How many times
have you let your team down?
You've nearly
gotten them all killed.
It's a wonder they haven't
abandoned you.
[grunting]
No.
We always
have each other's backs.
The Ninja are a team.
A team
you'll never be able to lead.
Not like Master Wu did.
Not even like Cole did.
-Ugh!
-Where do I even begin
with how my mistakes you've made
in your life, Lloyd?
Let's start with recently.
Arin went with Ras
because you were
such a bad mentor.
You lost Jay for so long
his goodness was shattered.
You ever wonder why Master Wu--
who's still alive--
hasn't even tried to come back?
He's too ashamed
of what a failure you've become.
Ah!
H'ah! H'yah!
You're just...
you're just trying
to manipulate me.
Get under my skin.
With the truth?
You know it's all true, Lloyd,
because I know it's true.
"Ninja never quit"?
You ever think
maybe you should quit?
That you have no idea
how to lead the Ninja,
and you only bring them harm?
They'd be better off
without you.
That...
that's not true!
H'yah!
Your failures know no limits.
You even managed
to anger the Source Dragons.
The most powerful beings
in the universe
are furious with you.
I know.
You caused them to destabilize
the entire Merged Lands!
Everything could end,
and it would all be your fault!
I know.
Whoa!
You've done more damage
to the Merged Lands than Ras.
More than any villain has.
You could not have brought
more destruction if you tried!
I know!
[grunting with impact]
H'yah!
But I had to anger
the Source Dragons
to save the world!
Huh.
Never expected
"The Chosen One"
to have so many excuses.
You'll never reach
your True Potential
as the Green Ninja
because your only potential
is failure.
For yourself,
and for those you love.
[gasping]
It's not too late.
It's never too late.
I can still prove
I'm the Chosen One!
H'yah!
[♪♪♪]
H'ah!
[alarm blaring]
[Loyalist #1]
This wasn't like this
when we put him in here, right?
There's no way he's still alive.
[Cole]
I'd say that's incorrect.
[Loyalist #1] Get back here!
[pounding on cell door]
[♪♪♪]
Is this wooden corkscrew
really as powerful
as they think?
-[alarms blaring]
-Seriously?
Come on!
Hey there.
Nice masks.
This probably looks bad, right?
Well...
[Loyalists yelping]
[Cole]
...it's gonna feel even worse!
H'yah!
[roaring battle cry]
[grunting with impact]
[force field powering down]
Gotcha!
[grunting]
[Cole] What the...?
What?
Wow!
Unexpected bonus.
[roaring]
You can't beat me,
because there's nothing
you can say
that I haven't already
said to myself.
Remember when Finn Tully
pantsed you in gym class?
[gasping]
[groaning]
[Enemy Lloyd
laughing maniacally]
I...
actually forgot about that.
[laughter echoing]
H'yah!
Look at you.
A boy pretending to be a man.
You never grew up,
and that's why
you're a mere shadow
of what Master Wu was!
That may be true,
but I--
You still don't know
what being the Green Ninja
really means.
How deluded and full of yourself
do you have to be
to think
you could master a power
you can't even understand?
I still--
It's only a matter of time
before the entire world falls
because of your failures
as a leader,
and the worst thing?
You're too clouded
by your own expectations
to realize you can't handle it.
That's what will destroy
your friends.
[♪♪♪]
[grunting]
[gasping]
This is the limit
of your potential.
[gasping]
[grunting in battle]
[monsters snarling]
[♪♪♪]
[telepathically]
It's as I foresaw...
-Ugh!
-Ah! -Ugh!
[Euphrasia] What is it?
Lloyd... is failing.
[Arin panting]
It can't be true.
Lloyd can't be failing.
I don't want to lose hope
either,
but we have to be real
about this,
or we're gonna fail next!
Ah!
What's that thing
you always tell me?
[Arin] Ninja never qui--
-Ah!
-[monster roaring]
[Zane grunting]
[snarling]
[Zane gasping]
[yelping]
H'yah!
Whoa!
[monster hissing]
[roaring]
[monsters snarling]
[Zane] I fear there is no hope.
[Cole roaring]
H'yah!
[Cole] Not so brave anymore?
[firing blasters]
Ugh!
[mech stomping]
You dare, Ninja?
[Cole] Empress Beatrix?
Heard a lot about you,
don't believe we've met.
Cole.
Now, let me guess.
You've got some evil plans.
Well, I'm here to crush them.
Oof.
You look different
than my friends described.
New haircut?
[growling] H'ah!
[roaring]
[Empress Beatrix] I have been
dreaming of this day,
of crushing all of the Ninja!
[grunting]
-Huh?
-[Beatrix laughing wickedly]
[Cole]
Was this part of your dream?
[roaring]
[empty blaster clicking]
[Cole] Hmm?
[roaring]
[Empress Beatrix shrieking]
[Cole roaring] H'yah!
[Cole] Whoa!
[crazed cackling]
[Cole gasping]
-[laughing maniacally]
-Ah! Oof!
[rocks crumbling]
This is mine,
and soon all of Imperium
will be mine again!
[♪♪♪]
[laughing maniacally]
[groaning in confusion]
[sighing]
This is getting to be a habit.
[grunting and struggling]
He wears that hat for real?
[laughing]
Oh, crud.
Behold,
I have acquired the mighty--
Dispense with
the formalities, please.
I told you there was no reason
to doubt me.
We shall see.
Bring the other sliver.
"Gebalow, Smegalow,
Carniff Fie...
Helagove, Tetrabo,
Lesto Sie..."
With one final word,
control will be yours, Empress.
"Bah-vaugnat."
Bah-vaugnat!
No, no, no, no, no...
[Empress Beatrix]
With this Weapon--
a weapon only one
as almighty as I
can wield--
I will lead us
to rightful glory,
and eliminate
all who dare defy me!
[chuckling]
I knew you weren't
strong enough
to face your own fears.
I never had a doubt about that.
Had you come
when you were younger,
you might've stood a chance,
but you've accrued
a lifetime of failures
to use against you.
You feel the weight of them
with every blow I strike,
and believe me,
I know how heavy your weakness
weighs on your soul,
so consider this a gift,
an escape from
all the mistakes you've made.
[grunting]
It's too late, Lloyd!
I can feel how much hate
is in your heart.
Yes! For you!
For us.
That rage?
It's hurt, it's shame,
it's fear with nowhere to go.
[Enemy Lloyd grunting]
I've made a lot of mistakes,
but without them,
I'd never have learned.
Mistakes are how we grow.
You are just my weaknesses
come to life,
and I won't give you
any more power.
You'll never be able to shake
the power of your own fears
and failures!
Ah!
[shattering]
[♪♪♪]
[Flow] We should have seen
his fate coming.
[Motion] It is a great loss
among mortals.
[Energy]
This cannot be his end.
The Legendary Green Ninja's
power is to enhance,
to connect.
He may have failed
the traditional trials,
but his true gift
his true potential,
is anything but traditional...
[♪♪♪]
[Lloyd] Each tree
is connected.
Trees are life.
I am the Master of Life.
[♪♪♪]
Lloyd...
[brakes screeching]
[gasping]
Did you just feel that?
[Arin grunting in battle]
[Euphrasia] What just happened?
I experienced it, too!
It was Lloyd.
It was like
I could feel his presence.
But why?
Did he... not survive?
If he didn't, we're doomed.
[♪♪♪]